NATALIA YARYSHEVA

Long Beach, CA 90802 | 562-533-6324 | n.yarysheva@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Personal Portfolio</u>

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

A former English Teacher, now a Front-End developer, always had a passion for learning so no wonder that after mastering languages switched to programming ones. With experience of living abroad and unique skills in cross-cultural collaboration. Highly creative, easily adaptable, attentive to details and experienced in JavaScript and React. Dream of working in an Agile environment at a mission-driven organization and building projects that create an impact.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6), Reac.js, SASS / SCSS, CSS, HTML, Git/GitHub, Firebase, Rest API, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

EDUCATION

University of Leeds

UK

PgDip in International Communications

09/2011 - 11/2013

Pyatigorsk State Linguistic University

Russia

BA in Linguistics and Intercultural Communication

09/2006 - 06/2011

Codecademy - Web development career path (300 hours), SASS, Navigation Design, Color Design **Udacity** - Object-oriented programming

Adobe certified center **Specialist** - Adobe Illustrator (level 1), Adobe Photoshop (level 2)

EXPERIENCE

Web developer (freelancer)

06/2022 - present

- Create websites, review aspiring web developers' code, advise them on user interface
- Come up with the best ways to explain coding concepts to total beginners

Aizhi Middle School China

ESL Teacher

05/2018 - 06/2022

- Organized and delivered comprehensive lessons for two grades simultaneously; improved students' scores by 22% during tenure
- Communicated with parents and educated them about learning materials when needed.

Bafus Russia 10/2017 - 04/2018

Jr Web developer

- Created and edited content for the web.
- Developed illustrations, logos and other designs in Photoshop/Illustrator.
- Participated in development of website according to business requirements (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) and ensured website is accessible across different platforms.
- Contributed to UX flows design.